Finding Aid for the Walter Gabrielson papers LSC.1830
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 5. Slides and photographs of artwork, 1962-2008
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- airplanes, 1968 -1991 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- Karl Bornstein representation, 1978-1982 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- humanist, 1979-1985 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- matted (folder 1 of 2), 1985 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- matted (folder 2 of 2), 1985 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- labeled, 1985-1992 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- commissions, 1985-1993 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- motels, ca. 1985-1995 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- sculptures, ca. 1987 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- sculptures, 1988-1992 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- sequential and women series, ca. 1989-1993 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- charcoal and pastel drawings, ca. 1990 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- horizontal paintings, 1990-1992 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- narrative studies, 1990-1993 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- San Diego series, ca. 1991-1992 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- faces, 1992-1993 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- humanist, 1992-1993 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- wall pieces, 1993-1997 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- small town, 1995-2000 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- various (folder 1 of 2), 1995 -1996 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    Includes small paintings series
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- various (folder 2 of 2), 1995 -1996 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    Includes airplanes and flower series
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- movie theaters, ca 1996-1998 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- western, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    Includes some small paintings from other series
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- surrealist series and wall pieces, 1998 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- food, ca. 2001 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - 4 x 5 transparencies -- poker faces, 2003-2005 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Negatives (bw) -- exhibition, ca. 1970 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    Includes shots of opening that may be Gabrielson's show at the Comsky gallery
  - Negatives (bw) -- early works, 1971-1973 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Negatives (bw) -- airplane, ca. 1972 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    Includes images of sculpture and Gabrielson's airplane
  - Negatives (bw) -- ArtSpace exhibition, ca. 1980 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Negatives -- commissions, 1986-1993 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Negatives (bw) -- wall sculptures, ca. 1987 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Negatives (bw) -- horizontal paintings, 1990-1992 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Negatives -- San Diego series, 1991-1992 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Negatives -- wall pieces, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Negatives -- Jill Thayer exhibition, 1997 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    Consists of images from an exhibition in Bakersfield, CA in the Jill Thayer gallery
  - Negatives -- kachinas, 2003-2004 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Negatives -- surrealist, 2003-2004 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Negatives -- various series, 2003-2004 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Negatives -- lawyer, 2003-2005 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Negatives -- poker faces, 2003-2005 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Negatives -- landscape paintings, 2004-2005 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Negatives -- food, 2008 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Photographs (bw 8x10) -- early works, 1971-1973 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Photographs (bw 8x10) -- drawings and paintings, 1976-1985 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Photographs (bw 8x10) -- ArtSpace exhibition, ca. 1980 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Photographs (polaroids) -- commissions and exhibitions, ca. 1984 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Photographs -- charcoal and pastel drawings, ca. 1990 (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Photographs -- Gabrielson with wall pieces, ca. 1994 (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Photographs -- exhibition at Jill Thayer Gallery, 1997 (Box 44, Folder 24)
    Consists of photographs from the opening and installation of an exhibition at Jill Thayer Gallery in Bakersfield, CA
  - Photographs -- San Diego series, 1998 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Photographs -- food, 2001-2008 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Photographs (8x10) -- small town paintings, ca. 2003 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Photographs -- lawyer art, 2003-2005 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Photographs -- kachinas, 2003-2005 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Photographs -- poker faces, 2003-2005 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Slides -- Gabrielson in Germany, 1959-1962 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    Slides taken while Gabrielson served in the Air Force stationed in Germany
  - Slides -- documentation of airplanes, 1968-1972 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    Slides taken while at the air field, air museum, and flying
  - Slides -- documentation of industrial machinery, 1968-1974 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    Includes images of an airplane project on which Gabrielson was working
  - Negatives -- Gabrielson and Fiske in Europe, ca. 1966 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Slides -- signs, 1969 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Slides -- Rose bowl, ca. 1976 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Slides -- doo dah parade, ca. 1978 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    Images from an eclectic parade begun in Pasadena in 1978
  - Slides -- Gabrielson in Hawaii, 1979 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Negatives -- documentation of the coverage of the LA riots, 1992 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Photographs -- documentation of the coverage of the LA riots, 1992 (Box 46, Folder 8)
- 6. Research Morgue, ca. 1974-2008
  Consists of Gabrielson's visual reference files that facilitated his artistic process. Largely consists of magazine clippings and newspaper articles.
  - Alphabetical: arts, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 47)
  - Alphabetical: arts-big and small, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 48)
  - Alphabetical: beach-cat, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 49)
  - Alphabetical: chairs-country store, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 50)
  - Alphabetical: court-fire, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 51)
  - Alphabetical: Florida-historical buildings, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 52)
  - Alphabetical: house-inside, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 53)
  - Alphabetical: interiors-LA riots, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 54)
  - Alphabetical: LA riots-music, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 55)
  - Alphabetical: music-presidents, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 56)
  - Alphabetical: portal-school, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 57)
  - Alphabetical: script-street, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 58)
  - Alphabetical: street vendor-urban, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 59)
  - Alphabetical: warehouse-women, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 60)
  - Alphabetical: women-vernacular, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 61)
  - Faces, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 62)
  - Food, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 63)
  - Food, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 64)
  - Landscape, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 65)
  - Landscape, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 66)
  - Landscape, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 67)
  - Landscape, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 68)
  - Landscape, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 69)
  - Landscape and nature, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 70)
  - Nature, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 71)
  - Nature and people, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 72)
  - People, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 73)
  - People, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 74)
  - People, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 75)
  - People and places, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 76)
  - Places and small town, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 77)
  - Small town, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 78)
  - Small town, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 79)
  - Sports, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 80)
  - Transportation and various, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 81)
  - Various and western, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 82)
  - Western, ca. 1974-2008 (Box 83)